<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Syrian Haven</string>
    <string name="usa_country_name">America</string>
    <string name="aus_country_name">Australia</string>
    <string name="cdn_country_name">Canada</string>
    <string name="deu_country_name">Germany</string>
    <string name="nor_country_name">Norway</string>

    <string name="usa_accepting_num">10,000</string>
    <string name="aus_accepting_num">12,000</string>
    <string name="cdn_accepting_num">45,000</string>
    <string name="deu_accepting_num">no limit</string>
    <string name="nor_accepting_num">8,000</string>

    <string name="usa_resettled_num">3,097</string>
    <string name="aus_resettled_num">26</string>
    <string name="cdn_resettled_num">26,262</string>
    <string name="deu_resettled_num">484,000</string>
    <string name="nor_resettled_num">11,246</string>

    <string name="usa_aid_num">$4.5 billion</string>
    <string name="aus_aid_num">$177 million</string>
    <string name="cdn_aid_num">$970 million</string>
    <string name="deu_aid_num">$3.15 billion</string>
    <string name="nor_aid_num">$356 million</string>

    <string name="usa_text">
        As of February 2016, the country had resettled 3,097 Syrians (up from 90 in 2013). Following
        the November 2015 Paris attacks, at least 27 state governors declared their refusal to accept
        refugees, or questioned the vetting process. The US State Department has
        affirmed that the country will accept 10,000 Syrian refugees in 2016. The USA has
        provided $4.5 billion to aid Syrian refugees as of late December 2015.
    </string>
    <string name="aus_text">
        In October 2015, Australia announced that it would accept 12,000 Syrian refugees. By
        February 2016, Australia had settled 26 refugees.
    </string>
        <string name="cdn_text">
            In July 2013, Canada promised to resettle 1,300 refugees by 2015 and pledged $100
            million in humanitarian aid. "No more than 10 [refugees had] arrived in Canada."
            by March 2014, and under public scrutiny leading into a national general election,
            the government agreed to resettle 11,300 refugees by the end of 2017, and then
            10,000 by September 2016. Following the 2015 general election, the newly elected
            government committed to bringing 25,000 refugees by the end of 2015. This
            deadline was moved to February 2016 to ensure thorough screening in the aftermath of the 2015 Paris Attacks. Canadians have expressed considerable interest in receiving refugees and Prime Minister Justin Trudeau met the first two flights on Dec 10 and Dec 13, 2015. To date Canada has arranged 96 flights to airlift refugees from their host countries, welcomed 25,000 refugees into 269 communities across the country, and agreed to resettle 35-50,000 refugees by the end of 2016.[167] Resettlement arrangements for additional refugees and social integration of arriving refugees is ongoing The cost over the next six years is estimated at (CDN) $564-million and $678-million.[168] The Prime Minister stated that the most vulnerable would be accepted first, including families, children and members of the LGBT communities Among the Syrian refugees accepted for resettlement are thousands of ethnic Armenians. On February 27, 2016 Canadian government declared that it had met its goal of resettling 25,000 Syrian refugees in Canada.
    </string>
        <string name="deu_text">
            In 2013, Germany received 11,851 asylum requests by Syrians, in 2014 the number more
            than tripled to 39,332. The German Federal Minister of the Interior estimated in
            March 2015, that some 105,000 Syrian refugees have been accepted by Germany. By
            June 2015, 161,435 Syrians resided in Germany, of which 136,835 had entered after
            January 2011.After suspending the Dublin rules for Syrian refugees, the numbers
            increased to the point of stressing Germany\'s infrastructure and logistic capabilities.
            From January to July 2015, the Bundesamt for Migration and Flüchtlinge (Federal office
            for migration and refugees) received 42,100 requests for asylum. By the end 2015,
            the figure had reached 158,657. 96 percent of the asylum requests were approved. It is
            estimated that 300,000 Syrian refugees are in the country. German Chancellor Angela
            Merkel has said that "The fundamental right to asylum for the politically persecuted knows no upper limit; that also goes for refugees who come to us from the hell of a civil war." German Chancellor Angela Merkel decided to let all Syrians enter the country but had to stop train travel to/from Austria to control the numbers arriving. At Munich\'s main railway station, thousands of Germans applauded Syrians as they arrived in September.The German police force announced on 22 October 2015 that they had prevented a planned attack on a refugee home in Bamberg by a right wing  extremist group. They also said there had been nearly 600 attacks on refugee homes in 2015, a sharp rise from 2014. As well, 19-39,000 (depending on estimates) of members of the German right wing Pegida movement rallied on 19 October 2015 in Dresden against accepting refugees. Some 14-20,000 other individuals held a counter rally in the town. On New Year\'s morning 2016, a group of about a thousand male migrants of North African or Arab descent sexually assaulted 600 females in Cologne. Angela Merkel\'s openness towards refugees was criticized and 61 percent of individuals in an INSA poll reported they were less happy about accepting refugees after the assaults. German feminist Alice Schwarzer said that the policy is causing Germany to have open doors for male violence, sexism, and antisemitism. Greece – Greece welcomes refugees when in transit to Germany to apply for refugee status.
            In 2015, there were 385,525 arrivals by sea. It is estimated that only
            8 percent of arrivals (31,000 Syrian refugees) applied for asylum in Greece,
            as most are in transit further into Europe. 15,000-17,000 refugees had landed
            on Lesbos island by September 2015, overwhelming the resources and generosity
            of local residents. Many refuges also make landfall at Agathonisi,
            Farmakonisi, Kos, Lemnos, Rhodes, Chios, Samos, Kastellorizo and other islands
            near Turkey. Some arrive via the Evros border crossing from Turkey. On 19
            February 2016 Austria imposed restrictions on the number of refugees entering
            the country followed by Slovenia, Croatia, Serbia and the Republic of
            Macedonia, of just 580 arrivals a day. As a result, large numbers of Syrian
            refugees and migrants from other countries are stuck in Greece. On 22
            February 2016 at an emergency summit on the migrant crisis in Brussels it was
            agreed that another 100,000 spaces in refugee reception centres will be
            created. 50,000 spaces in Greece and another 50,000 spaces in Balkan
            countries.Given that 2 – 3,000 migrants arrive in Greece every day,
            these 100,000 spaces look inadequate.
        </string>
    <string name="nor_text">
        Norway has announced it will accept 8,000 refugees from Syria under the UN quota
        system by the end of 2017
    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
</resources>
